MICHAEL YALEKHUE

Phone: <u>+44 7868666451</u> | Email: <u>yalexmickey@gmail.com</u> | United Kingdom GitHub: <u>github.com/aulphar</u> Website: <u>michaelyalekhue.netlify.app</u>

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/michael-valekhue

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution-oriented .NET Software Developer with experience designing and implementing scalable, secure solutions and web application development for complex systems across diverse industries. Possess working knowledge in web services technologies, microservice architecture, and development of Service-Oriented Applications (SOA) based on Rest APIs using Microsoft .NET Framework.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Microsoft.NET
- Blazor
- C#
- Microservices

- JavaScript, Angular
- SQL Server, MYSQL, MongoDB
- Smart Contracts

- Cloud Services Microsoft Azure
- Docker
- Azure DevOps
- Unit Testing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Costa Investment Properties Limited - Nottingham, UK Junior .NET Developer

Mar 2024 - Jun 2024

Built and maintained an innovative Property Management Solution using Angular and API technologies. The solution offers
homeowners and tenants an intuitive online software platform for managing property services, including tenant information
management, payment processing, generation of financial reports, and more.

The tools used in the development of this project are:

.NET 7, Angular, JavaScript, SQL Server, Docker, Microsoft Azure, Git.

- Designed and implemented a user-friendly expense tracking system within the property management software ensuring accurate and efficient recording of all expenses associated with each property. Collaborating with a cross-functional team, I integrated expense tracking with other modules such as rent collection, maintenance, and financial reporting. Additionally I developed features for categorizing expenses, uploading receipts, and setting up recurring expenses to streamline property management task.
- Engaged in comprehensive system study and proficient in database engineering tasks, including the creation of databases, tables, intricate stored procedures, and SQL Performance Tuning. These efforts have significantly improved data manipulation capabilities and ensure enhanced consistency.
- Experience with dependency injection containers, applying S.O.L.I.D design principles, and developing applications within an Azure environment.

Triversa Solutions Limited Junior .NET Developer

Aug 2021 - Feb 2022

• Developed a financial and Anti-Money Laundering (AML) reporting enterprise application for government cooperation and banking institutions. This project was built using a microservice architecture leveraging tools including Azure Service Bus, SQL Server, Docker. It consisted of three services (the core AML application used to flag suspicious transactions, the AML reporting solution used to report transactions in various format including JSON, XML, and Excel, and an ETL application used for extracting and managing customer data).

The tools used in the development of this project are:

.NET 5, and later updated to .NET 6, JavaScript, SQL Server, Oracle, Docker, Microsoft Azure, Git.

Developed and provided support in the development of a Failed Bank Management System. A Deposit Insurance Solution for the
Nigeria Deposit Insurance Corporation (NDIC), that enhances quick resolution of failed banks by paying all stakeholders (Depositors,
Creditors, and Shareholders) from funds recovered for failed banks from Loan Recoveries, Sales of bank-owned Physical Assets and
Investments, and collateral sales from judgement enforcement.

The tools used in the development of this project are:

.NET v4.7, JavaScript, Telerik reporting, SQL Server, IIS, Git.

- Responsible for designing and developing an ETL process to efficiently handle a large volume of customer data.
- Optimized performance and scalability of intricate SQL stored procedures through thorough tuning efforts.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Computer Science	
Benson Idahosa University	2019 - 2023
Relevant Modules: Artificial Intelligence, Software Development Life Cycle, Novel Interaction	
Advanced Diploma in Software Engineering (ADSE)	
Aptech World Wide	2018 - 2019
	Benson Idahosa University Relevant Modules: Artificial Intelligence, Software Development Life Cycle, Novel Interaction Advanced Diploma in Software Engineering (ADSE)